TV를 볼 때에는 밝은 방에서 적당히 떨어져서 보도록 해!
While you're watching the television...
Selama menonton acara ini
...be sure to keep your distance and watch in a well-lit room!
pastikan berada di jarak yang cukup dan di ruangan yang terang!
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Dennou Boukenki
Series Composition
Chief Director
Sekijima Mayori
Okajima Kunitoshi
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
Concept Design
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Kawami Takuya
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Oikawa Neko
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Kachihide Yuki
Nomura Hiroshi
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
Director
Negishi Hiroshi
Production
악의 프로그램 데리트로스에게 침략당한 매지컬 게이트는
Once completely invaded by Deletloss, Magical Gate is now about 90% recovered
Berkat aksi Webknight pembela kebenaran, Gladion, dan Webdiver-nya, Yuuki Kento,
정의의 웹나이트 글라디온과 웹다이버 유우키 켄토의 활약으로 90%가 복구되었다.
thanks to Gladion the Webknight of justice and his Webdiver Yuuki Kento.
Magical Gate yang dikuasai program jahat Deletloss sudah 90% bisa direbut kembali.
그러나 매지컬 게이트의 기반을 이루는 제일 중요한 에이리어, 타임 에이리어에서는
But, at the most important area that supports the whole Magical Gate, Time Area,
Tapi, di Time Area, area terpenting yang menopang Magical Gate dari dasar,
월드 링크 관리국의 주동력을 폭파하려고 하는 다이탈리온 프로그램이 작동하고 있었다.
Ditalion program started to move and make World Link Administration Center's main computer explode.
program pengendali Ditalion mulai bergerak dan berusaha untuk meledakkan komputer utama stasiun pengendali World Link.
켄토의 아버지 유우키 타케토는 다이탈리온 프로그램을 파괴하기 위해
Kento's father, Yuuki Taketo, dived into Magical Gate
Untuk menghancurkan program Ditalion, ayah Kento, Yuuki Taketo
네오다이브 시스템으로 매지컬 게이트에 다이브했다.
using Neodive System in order to destroy Ditalion Program.
masuk ke dalam Magical Gate dengan sistem Neodive.
글라디온에게 연락을 받은 켄토는 타임 에이리어에 가기로 마음을 먹는다.
After hearing from Gladion, Kento decided to go to Time Area.
Setelah mendapat panggilan dari Gladion, Kento pun bergerak menuju Time Area.
켄토를 기다리는 자는 누구인가.
What awaits Kento inside?
Apa yang sudah menanti Kento di sana?
시간의 신 다이탈리온이 다이버랜드를 폭파하기까지 7시간.
7 hours until Ditalion, the god of time, blows up Diverland.
Tinggal 7 jam lagi sampai Diverland meledak akibat ulah Ditalion, sang dewa waktu.
궁극합체! 다이탈리온 프라임
Ultimate Fusion! Ditalion Prime
Gabungan Terkuat! Ditalion Prime
매지컬 게이트에 플러그 잇!
To Magical Gate, Plug It!
Menuju Magical Gate, Plug It!
아빠, 잠깐만 기다려. 지금 바로 구하러 가.
Dad, wait for me. I'm going to save you right now.
Ayah, tunggulah aku. Aku akan segera menolongmu.
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
긴급 발진 대기중.
Emergency dispatch, standby.
Siap untuk diluncurkan.
글라디온, 출동.
Gladion, shoot.
웹체인지! 글라디온, 파이터 모드!
Webchange! Gladion, Fighter Mode!
글라디온, 빅토리 모드!
Gladion, Victory Mode!
웹체인지! 와이버리온, 윙 모드!
Webchange! Wyverion, Wing Mode!
빅토리 글라디온!
Victory Gladion!
가자!
Let's do this!
Ayo!
나타났군!
You finally show yourself!
Keluar juga kau!
나는 시간의 신. 오늘이야말로 마지막 전투다, 글라디온!
I am the god of time. Today shall be our last day, Gladion!
Aku adalah dewa waktu. Ini akan jadi pertarungan terakhir kita, Gladion!
바라던 바다!
As you wish!
Itu yang kuinginkan!
모두!
Everyone!
Teman-teman!
결국 찾아냈다!
We finally found you!
Akhirnya ketemu!
더 이상 네가 원하는 대로는 되지 않을 테다!
I won't let you do as you like!
Tidak akan kubiarkan kau bertindak seenaknya lagi!
잘 들으셨겠지요!
Like he said!
Ya, itu benar!
가자!
Let's go!
Ayo!
나는 다이탈리온. 나에게 반항하는 자는 소멸해라!
I am Ditalion. I will terminate anyone who defies me!
Aku Ditalion. Yang berani menentangku akan kumusnahkan!
다이타 액스!
Dita Axe!
모, 몸이!
My body!
Ba-badanku!
재규어온! 그리피온!
Jaguaron! Griffion!
샤크온! 피닉스온!
Sharkon! Phoenixon!
잘한다! 와이버리온!
Good job, Wyverion!
Bagus, Wyverion!
가자! 글라디온!
Let's go, Gladion!
Maju, Gladion!
힘이... 우리도 지지 않아!
When it comes to power, we won't lose!
Dalam hal kekuatan, kami tidak akan kalah!
무기 선택: 그란매그넘
Weapon Selection: Granmagnum
Pilihan Senjata: Granmagnum
그란매그넘!
Granmagnum!
빅토리 슛!
Victory Shoot!
현재 힘이 막상막하라는 것인가.
It seems their powers are even until now.
Kelihatannya sampai saat ini kekuatan mereka seimbang.
이 틈에 유우키 군을 찾아라.
We'll search for Taketo while they're fighting.
Selagi mereka bertarung, kita akan mencari Taketo.
네.
Got it.
Baik.
지면 안 돼, 글라디온.
You can't lose, Gladion.
Jangan sampai kalah, Gladion.
정신 꼭 차려, 켄토.
Hang in there, Kento.
Kento, bertahanlah.
나는 다이탈리온.
I am Ditalion.
Aku adalah Ditalion.
일어나라! 페가시온! 라이거온!
Wake up! Pegasion! Ligeron!
Bukalah mata kalian! Pegasion! Ligeron!
라이거온. 페가시온.
Ligeron? Pegasion?
웹합체! 다이탈리온 프라임!
Webfusion! Ditalion Prime!
다이탈리온 프라임...
Ditalion Prime...
다이탈리온 프라임이라는 웹나이트에 대한 데이터는 없어뾰꼬!
No data about Ditalion Prime exists-pyoko!
Ditalion Prime tidak ada dalam data Webknight-pyoko!
켄토. 네가 원하는 대로 될 것 같니.
Kento, I won't let you do things as you like.
Kento, tidak akan kubiarkan kau terus berbuat seenaknya.
해치워버리자고.
Let's bring an end to this.
Mari kita akhiri ini.
프라임 소드!
Prime Sword!
프라임 랜서!
Prime Lancer!
다이탈리온이 강해졌어!
Ditalion has powered up!
Kekuatan Ditalion meningkat!
안돼!
T-This is bad!
Ini gawat!
유우키 군의 행방은 아직 모르는가?
Is Yuuki's location not available yet?
Apakah keberadaan Taketo masih belum diketahui?
네, 아직입니다.
No, not yet.
Iya, masih belum.
다이버랜드 폭파까지 8시간...
8 hours until Diverland is destroyed...
Kehancuran Diverland tinggal 6 jam lagi...
여긴 어디지?
Where am I?
Ini... tempat apa ini?
카이토! 카이토니?
Kaito! Is that Kaito?
Kaito? Kamu Kaito, kan?
아, 아빠야?
Dad?
Ayah?
카이토!
Kaito!
아빠!
Dad!
Ayah!
카이토!
Kaito!
외로웠어! 아무도 없어서!
I was lonely! Nobody was here!
Aku kesepian, Ayah! Tidak ada seorangpun di sini!
-아빠!
-응, 그 동안 힘냈구나.
-Dad!
-You did a splendid job.
-Ayah!
-Kau sudah berjuang keras.
여긴 대체 어디야?
What is this place, anyway?
Tempat ini... tempat apa ya?
매지컬 게이트의 어딘가인건 확실한데...
I'm sure we're in somewhere of Magical Gate...
Tidak salah lagi, kalau ini adalah suatu tempat di Magical Gate.
카이토, 혹시 아니?
Kaito, do you know?
Kaito, apakah kau tahu di mana ini?
몰라. 난 아무것도 몰라!
I don't. I don't know what's happening here!
Aku tidak tahu. Aku tidak tahu apa yang sedang terjadi!
괜찮아. 걱정마.
It's all right. Chill out.
Sudahlah, Kaito. Tidak apa-apa.
불쌍한 녀석. 혼자서 잘 힘내줬구나. 어쨌든 한시라도 빨리 여기서 탈출하지 않으면 더 이상 남은 시간은 없을 텐데.
I pity him. He did a good job survivng by himself.
Kasihan sekali. Dia sudah berjuang seorang diri.
Anyway, we must get out of this place as soon as possible. There must be only a few hours left.
Yang penting, kami harus segera keluar dari sini. Waktu yang tersisa pasti sudah hampir habis.
자세를 고쳐, 글라디온!
Stand up again, Gladion!
Berdirilah kembali, Gladion!
점점 아슬아슬해지고 있어뾰꼬!
The battle is getting more dangerous-pyoko!
Ini menjadi semakin berbahaya-pyoko!
우리 동작이 꿰뚫어보이나 봐!
He foresees our moves!
Dia sudah bisa menebak serangan kita!
젠장, 어떻게 뭘 할 수 없나!
Damn, can't we do anything?!
Sial, tak adakah hal lain yang bisa kita lakukan?!
안 돼. 이 초중력에서는.
No. Not in this supergravitiy.
Tidak, tidak di dalam supergravitasi ini.
모두 현혹되면 안돼!
Everyone! Don't get fooled!
Semuanya! Jangan tertipu!
그래! 그건 속임수에 불과해!
Yeah! That's nothing more than a trick!
Benar! Itu hanyalah sebuah tipuan!
이 목소리는!
This voice!
Suara ini!
케르베리온! 오르토리온!
Kerberion! Orthorion!
웹합체! 골렘온!
Webfusion! Golemon!
골렘온!
Golemon!
Brought to you by Subdiver
스파이럴 커터!
Spiral Cutter!
골렘온!
Golemon!
-덕분에 살았어, 골렘온!
-근데 어떻게?
-Thank you, Golemon!
-But how did you do it?
-Terima kasih, Golemon!
-Tapi, bagaimana caranya?
너희들은 다이탈리온 프로그램의 속임수에 넘어갔다.
All of you fell to Ditalion Prime's trick.
Kalian semua telah diperdaya oleh tipuan Ditalion Prime.
초중력 따윈 애초에 없었어!
There is no such thing as supergravity from the start!
Hal seperti supergravitasi itu tidak ada dari awal!
단지 에너지에 휩쓸렸을 뿐이야!
You guys were just overran by energy!
Itu hanyalah sebuah pusaran energi!
그걸 스파이럴 커터로 날려버린 거군?
And that's why you blew it off with Spiral Cutter!
Makanya kau gunakan Spiral Cutter untuk menghilangkannya.
대단하군요!
That's amazing!
Luar biasa!
우리는 완벽한 웹나이트니까.
That's because we're the perfect Webknights.
Itu karena kami adalah Webknight yang sempurna.
어떠냐, 다이탈리온! 우리에게는 마음이 통하는 동료가 있어!
How's that, Ditalion! We have friends who understand each other!
Kau lihat itu, Ditalion?! Kami punya teman yang mengerti satu sama lain!
-웃기고 있네.
-그걸로 우릴 이길 수 있다고 생각하진 마렴.
-That's plain lame.
-Don't think you can defeat us by that.
Payah sekali.
Jangan kira kau bisa mengalahkan kami hanya dengan itu.
나는 시간의 신. 나에게 대드는 자는 소멸한다!
I am god of time. Whoever defies me will disappear!
Aku adalah dewa waktu. Yang berani menentangku akan kumusnahkan!
자이언트 드릴!
Giant Drill!
어떤 공격도 우리에겐 통하지 않아!
Your attack won't have any effects on us!
Serangan seperti itu tidak akan melukai kami!
스파이럴 커터!
Spiral Cutter!
글라디온. 저 녀석들이 많이 힘들어하는데 우리가 일단 모두 데리고 돌아갈게.
Gladion. Everyone's too tired to fight so I'm going to take them back to the station.
Gladion, Jaguaron dan yang lain sudah kelelahan. Aku akan membawa mereka kembali ke markas.
-알겠다.
-미안, 글라디온.
-I understand.
-Sorry, Gladion.
-Aku mengerti.
-Maaf, Gladion.
좋아. 그란블레이드로 단번에 끝장내 버리자!
Good. Now let's settle this at once with Granblade!
Baiklah. Ayo kita selesaikan pertarungan ini dengan Granblade!
그란블레이드!
Granblade!
이걸로 끝이야!
This is the end!
Akan kuselesaikan dengan ini!
빅토리 참!
Victory Slash!
안 돼.
I can't.
Aku tidak bisa.
왜 그래, 글라디온?
What's wrong, Gladion?
Kenapa, Gladion?
돌아가! 켄토!
Go back, Kento!
Kento, kembalilah!
뭐, 뭔 짓이야! 글라디온!
What are you doing?! Gladion!
A-Apa yang kau lakukan? Gladion!
대체 왜, 왜 그래! 글라디온!
Why? Why are you doing this, Gladion?!
Kenapa? Kenapa kau lakukan ini, Gladion!
뭔 일일까. 왜 공격하다 말고 다이브 아웃 시켰을까?
What's wrong with him?  Why abruptly stopping to attack and forcing me to dive out?
Apa yang terjadi dengannya? Kenapa berhenti menyerang dan memaksaku dive out?
조금만 더 있었으면 다이탈리온도 끝장인데.
Just a little more and Ditalion could've been defeated.
Padahal sedikit lagi Ditalion bisa dikalahkan.
이렇게는 안 돼. 다시 한번 플러그 잇!
I can't just stay put. Let's Plug It once more!
Aku tidak bisa diam saja. Akan kucoba Plug It sekali lagi!
매지컬 게이트에 플러그 잇!
To Magical Gate, Plug It!
Menuju Magical Gate, Plug It!
매지컬 게이트에 플러그 잇!
To Magical Gate, Plug It!
Menuju Magical Gate, Plug It!
이게 진짜!
This damned-
Sekali lagi!
뭔 일인가?
What's going on?
Apa yang terjadi?
글라디온으로부터 무언가가 분리했습니다.
Something has separated from Gladion.
Ada sesuatu yang keluar dari Gladion.
힘이 눈에 띄게 약해지고 있습니다.
His power is going down significantly.
Kekuatannya menurun dengan signifikan.
글라디온으로부터 뭔가 분리했다?
Something has separated from Gladion?
Sesuatu telah keluar dari Gladion?
설마...
That must be...
Jangan-jangan...
젠장! 망할!
Damn! Plug It already!
Sial! Ayolah!
켄토!
Kento!
-켄토!
-Kento!
마치 같은 곳을 빙글빙글 돌고 있는 것 같구나.
It's like we're going all over the same place.
Rasanya seperti kita berkeliling di tempat yang sama.
형은 잘 하고 있을까.
I wonder how would be my brother doing.
Bagaimana keadaan Kakak saat ini, ya?
-아, 켄토?
-형하고 약속했어.
-Ah, Kento?
-I promised with him.
-Oh, Kento?
-Aku telah berjanji dengan Kakak,
꼭 아빠부터 검도에서 한 방 날리겠다고!
that we will get a strike on you in Kendo!
kalau kami pasti akan mendapat satu poin dari Ayah di kendo!
그랬지. 둘의 마음을 하나로 모아 치면 반드시 한 번은 칠 수 있다고 했었지.
True. I did say that if you two combine your hearts when you attack,
Benar juga. Aku pernah bilang kalau kalian menyatukan hati kalian saat menyerang,
you'll definitely be able to get a strike from me.
kalian pasti bisa mendapat satu poin dariku, ya.
그리고 형하고 매지컬 게이트에 놀러 오고,
And after that, Bro and I went playing to Magical Gate.
Dan setelah itu, aku dan Kakak pergi bermain ke Magical Gate.
그리고 더 기억 안나!
And then... I can't remember!
Terus... aku tidak ingat lagi setelah itu!
괜찮아. 신경 쓸 필요 없어, 카이토. 그 때 말했듯이, 마음을 하나로 모을 수만 있다면 힘은 무한대가 된다고.
It's all right. Don't worry, Kaito.
Tidak apa-apa. Tak usah dipikirkan lagi, Kaito.
As I told before, when you combine your hearts into one, you will have an unlimited power.
Seperti yang sudah kubilang, dengan menyatukan hati kalian, kekuatan kalian akan jadi tak terbatas.
응.
Yeah.
Iya.
카이토. 아빠. 그리고 켄토. 지금 이 셋의 마음은 하나로 묶여 있어. 반드시 괜찮을 거야.
Dad, Kento and you. Right now, even if we three are separated, our hearts are still one. We'll be okay.
Kaito, Ayah, dan Kento.
Saat ini, walaupun kita terpisah, hati kita masih tersatukan. Kita pasti akan baik-baik saja.
-무한대의 힘을 믿어 봐.
-응!
-Believe in the limitless power.
-I will!
-Percayalah dengan kekuatan tanpa batas itu.
-Iya!
그랬구나...
I see.
Begitu...
글라디온이 켄토를 강제로 다이버랜드에 돌려보낸 건 분명 이유가 있겠지.
There must be a reason that Gladion sent you back to Diverland.
Pasti ada alasan dibalik mengapa Gladion mengembalikanmu secara paksa ke Diverland.
그게 뭔지는 나도 몰라.
But I don't know what it might be.
Tapi, aku tidak tahu kira-kira apa alasannya.
그래도 그렇지, 지금 당장 한시가 급한데!
The problem is we're running out of time here.
Masalahnya, kita juga sedang dikejar oleh waktu.
어떻게든 글라디온에게 돌아가야 해.
I must go back to Gladion no matter how.
Bagaimanapun juga, aku harus kembali ke Gladion.
그래! 켄토 아버지가 매지컬 게이트에 간 방법은?
I got an idea! How about using the method Kento's dad used to go to Magical Gate?
Aku tahu! Cara yang digunakan ayah Kento untuk pergi ke Magical Gate!
아, 그거다!
Ah, that's it!
Ah! Itu dia!
네오다이브 시스템이 있는 곳은 제 7 연구실!
Let's go to the research room 7 where Neodive System is at!
Neodive System! Itu terletak di ruang penelitian nomor 7!
경비아저씨가 있네...
There are guards...
Ada penjaganya...
사실을 말한다고 해도 들어가지 못하게 할 것 같아.
I don't think they'll let us in even if we tell the reason.
Aku rasa mereka tidak akan mengijinkan kita masuk.
그게 뭐라고! 우린 네 명이야! 달려들면 이기겠지!
Relax! There's four of us! If we strike them down, we'll win!
Tenang saja! Kita, kan, berempat! Kalau kita serbu, pasti kita menang!
그런 문제가 아니잖아!
That's not the problem!
Masalahnya bukan itu!
아저씨들 앞에선 우리가 뭔 짓을 해도 얘들 놀이겠지! 싸워봤자 안 될 테니까 그냥 잠시 떼어낼 방법이나 생각해.
If only they could stay away from there even if just for a while...
Coba kalau mereka menjauh dari situ walaupun hanya sebentar, ya...
아! 아까 불꽃놀이에서 남은 폭죽 있어?
I know! Anyone got a firecracker?
Aku tahu! Ada yang punya kembang api?
-폭죽?
-야, 켄토, 이번엔 뭘 하려고 그래.
-Firecracker?
-Come on, Kento, playing that at this is time is just...
-Kembang api?
-Hei, Kento, masa di saat seperti ini malah main kembang api?
-놀려고 하는 거 아니야!
-그렇게 말해봤자...
-I'm not thinking to play!
-What else can you use it but to play?
-Bukan buat main-main!
-Kalau bukan buat main, lalu buat apa lagi?
그럴 형편이 못 될 텐데... 아, 아까 폭죽 남은 거라면 있긴 해.
This is not a time to play around... Ah, there's a leftover from the festival.
Ini bukan saat yang tepat... Ah, sepertinya sisa kembang api yang waktu itu masih ada.
-쟌. 관리국에 로봇 청소기 있지?
-아마...
-Jean. There must be a robot cleaner here, right?
-Probably...
-Jean, di stasiun pengendali ada alat pembersih otomatis, kan?
-Mungkin...
-빨리 찾아 줘.
-응.
-Please get it quickly.
-Will do.
-Tolong cepat kau ambilkan, ya.
-Baiklah.
뭔 생각을 하는 거야.
What are you actually going to do?
Apa rencanamu sebenarnya?
누구야, 이걸 여기에 가지고 오다니!
Who dares doing this prank?!
Hei, siapa yang melakukan ini?!
그래! 지금이야!
Now!
Bagus! Saatnya!
음...
Uh...
Um...
빨리!
Quick!
Ayo!
잘 된 것 같네!
Everything seems be working well!
Sepertinya berjalan lancar, ya!
어쨌든, 저거야!
Aside from that, that's it!
Itu alat yang aku maksud.
아빠...
Dad...
Ayah...
이제 됐어. 고마워, 아오이.
I'm ready. I'm leaving it to you, Aoi.
Aku sudah siap sekarang. Tolong ya, Aoi.
이번엔 뭔 일인가! 아오이! 켄토! ...안돼!
Now what is it this time? Aoi! Kento! No!
Sedang apa mereka? Aoi! Kento... celaka!
-다 됐어.
-알았어.
-It's all ready.
-Got it.
-Aku rasa sudah bisa.
-Oke.
-잘 다녀와, 켄토.
-응.
-You ready, Kento?
-Of course.
-Bersiaplah, Kento.
-Baiklah.
멈춰!
Stop!
Hentikan!
-아리스가와 박사님...
-할아버지...
-Prof. Arisugawa...
-Grandpa...
-Kakek...
아오이. 모두들. 켄토 군! 이 장치가 뭔지 알고 있긴 한가!
Aoi. You guys too. Kento, do you really know what this device is for?!
Aoi, dan kalian. Apa Kento tidak tahu, untuk apa peralatan ini, hah?!
이 전송장치의 에너지는 단 일회용이다.
This transmission device can be used for only once.
Peralatan pemindah energi itu hanya bisa digunakan untuk satu kali.
일회용...
Just once...
Untuk satu kali...
게다가 지금 매지컬 게이트 안의 공간은 불안정하고 위험한 상태이다!
Furthermore, the hyperspace inside Magical Gate is very unstable right now,
Ditambah lagi, sekarang, kondisi di Magical Gate sedang sangat tidak stabil,
making the situation even more dangerous!
dan situasinya sangat berbahaya!
다이브하면 돌아오지 못하게 될 지도 모른다.
You might won't be able to return after diving.
Kalau melakukan dive, ada kemungkinan tidak bisa kembali lagi.
아빠를 구하고 싶은 네의 마음은 알겠으나 저 위험한 곳에 가게 할 수는 없다!
While I do understand your will to save your father, I will not let you do such dangerous gamble!
Aku mengerti perasaanmu yang ingin menolong ayahmu,
tapi aku tidak bisa membiarkanmu melakukan taruhan yang sangat berbahaya!
일단 네가 뭘 하려 했는지 말해 보거라.
What can you do by going there, anyway?
Lagipula, memangnya apa yang bisa kau lakukan dengan pergi ke sana?
또 같은 곳이구나.
It's the same place again.
Lagi-lagi tempat yang sama.
그래도,
Even so,
Biar begitu,
전 뭔 일이 있어도 가야만 해요.
I must go there no matter what happens.
apapun yang terjadi, aku harus pergi ke sana.
-저라면 아빠를 구할 수 있습니다.
-켄토!
-I can save my father.
-Kento!
-Aku pasti bisa menolong ayahku.
켄토 군, 그럼...
Kento, you're...
Kento, kau ini...
일단은 말씀드릴 수 없어요.
I cannot tell you why...
Aku tidak bisa mengatakan alasannya.
할아버지, 그렇게 해줘.
Grandpa, please.
Kakek, aku mohon.
무언가가 분리했다고?
Something separated?
Ada sesuatu yang keluar!
설마, 켄토,
Kento, are you...
Jangan-jangan, kau ini...
저는,
I am...
Aku...
오늘까지 저는 글라디온과 함께 싸워 왔습니다.
I've been fighting along with Gladion up until today.
Selama ini, aku terus bertarung bersama Gladion.
글라디온은 저를 기다리고 있어요. 전 돌아가야만 해요!
Gladion is waiting for me. I must go back!
Saat ini, Gladion sedang menungguku. Aku harus kembali ke sana!
저는 글라디온의 웹다이버, 유우키 켄토입니다!
I am Gladion's Webdiver, Yuuki Kento!
Aku adalah Webdiver Gladion, Yuuki Kento!
Screenplay
Kishima Nobuaki
Storyboarding
Staging
Oda Mihiro
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Kobayashi Yumiko
Gladion
Sugita Tomokazu
Arisugawa Aoi
Kikuchi Shiho
Asaba Naoki
Takeuchi Junko
Karon
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Jean J. Jekyll
Nakai Masataka
Yuuki Kaito
Takagi Reiko
Yuuki Taketo
Ookura Masaaki
Arisugawa Professor
Tobita Nobuo
Kurachi Rena
Kakazu Yumi
Hara Tsubasa
Itou Miyako
Voice Actor
Jaguaron
Kawashima Tokuyoshi
Sharkon
Yoshino Hiroyuki
Griffion
Nakamura Yuuichi
Phoenixon
Suzumura Ken'ichi
Kerberion
Miyashita Michio
Orthorion
Suyama Akio
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Oikawa Neko
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kouno Yougo
Singer
Kageyama Hironobu
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
Production
Thank you for watching!
다음 이야기 미리보기
Preview for Next Episode
Episode Selanjutnya
아빠하고 카이토를 인질로 잡다니,
You took my dad and Kaito as hostages?
Bisa-bisanya kau menjadikan ayahku dan Kaito sebagai sandera.
비겁해, 다이탈리온!
How cowardly of you, Ditalion!
Pengecut kau, Ditalion!
이대로라면 글라디온이 싸울 수 없잖아! 박사님, 제발!
Gladion can't fight against him like this! Please, professor!
Kalau begini terus, Gladion tidak bisa melawannya! Kumohon, profesor!
절 다이탈리온 안에 다이브하게 해 주세요!
Let me dive into Ditalion!
Tolong buat aku dive ke dalam Ditalion!
모두를 구하기 위해선 이 밖에는 방법이 없어요!
To save everybody, this is the only thing we can do!
Hanya cara ini yang bisa dilakukan untuk menyelamatkan semuanya!
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !